Dhruv Bahl Speak_

bhldhruv@gmail.com | 2508990360 | LinkedIn | Github | Kelowna, BC | He/Him

Summary

A 4th year computer science major at the University of British Columbia with 1.5 years work experience through internships involving database querying, APIs and testing and a personal interest in becoming a full stack developer

Skills (Years of experience listed after each item.)

Languages: Python 0.5 | JavaScript 0.5 | Java 2 | C# 1 | Typescript 0.5

Frameworks: React 1 |

Databases: MongoDB 0.5 | MySql 1

Other: Git 2 | Agile 1

Education

BSc in Computing, Computer Science, Graduation: 05/2023

University Of British Columbia, Canada

GPA: 3.3 / 4.00

Outstanding International Student award

Experience

Microsoft - Kelowna, British Columbia | Engineering Intern | 05/2020 - 08/2020

- Developed a program that can detect anomalies from transactional data using C# and SQL and displayed the anomalies on a webpage provided by Microsoft.
- Set up rule-based filtering that included filters based on unusually large purchase orders as well as random spikes in the tax rate to prevent displeased customers and loss of contracts.
- This is a company requirement and has saved on-call engineers time by 50% as the anomaly information
 was available on the webpage.

Microsoft - Kelowna, British Columbia | Engineering Intern | 05/2021 - 08/2021

- Responsible for the creation of an API using C#. The API's role was to change the payment date for an order
 if a new future date has been provided.
- Helped reduce clients' products from being disabled incorrectly.
- Created an end-to-end anomaly detection service that used technologies such as SCOPE and Azure Data Factory as well as C# to create another API with a similar implementation.

Skytrac - Kelowna, BC | Hardware/Software Test Co-op | 01/2022 - 12/2022

- Created a python script to identify high periods of latency in a csv file which reduces testing time for testers by 20% each time the test is run.
- Added to Skytrac's suite of Selenium test cases to test their flight tracking website. These automated test
 cases test the functionality of Skyweb (A flight tracking service). This will help reduce the time spent on
 these tests by testers by up to 200 hours.

Resume powered by Speak_

Dhruv Bahl Speak

 Contributed to the development of a software test tool (Avionic Data Bus Simulator) using C#. On completion, the test tool is estimated to be able to create 2000 tests a day

Projects

CheckLick | Capstone

- Implemented and redesigned 6 webpages by adding the CSS framework, Bootstrap, resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement compared to before.
- Participated in each step of the product development process from the group ideation to developing improvements for features that reach thousands of customers.

Car Payment calculator | Personal Project

- Solo project to understand and improve my knowledge of working with react and the native hooks such as useState and useEffect.
- Created a dynamic webpage with a form that updates the estimated payment dynamically.
- Additional work will be done to improve styling.

The Snake Game | Personal Project

- Solo project to understand and improve my knowledge of Java's OOP structure and its GUI.
- A continuous project as I aim to add more features to make it more fun and continuously tap into the creative part of my mind.

An Employee Portal | solo project

- Another solo project that targets the overall application of react. This project was done using typescript instead of javascript to improve my understanding of how the two work together.
- The portal calls a public API endpoint to create fake users therefore exploring how axios works. The aim is to ease my way into full-stack development.
- The employee portal shows the total number of employees, allowing for viewing, adding, editing and deleting employees.